# **CURRICULUM - VITAE**

**Hiten Kumar** 

Mail ID: - Hiten222@gmail.com Mobile no: - +91-9827892233

Mobile 110.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced Information Security Manger with skills in diverse range of Information and Cyber security technologies, IT Infrastructure and Service Delivery. Implementation Knowledge of ISO 27001:2005 and Information security audit based on RBI Master Direction.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Overall, 14+ years of experience in handling IT services, information security, cloud security, Service delivery that includes over four years of information security compliance management.

Proficient and knowledgeable in vulnerability assessments, SOC, identifying issues, security risk analysis, analyzing system requirements for internal audit and regulatory reporting. Adept in development and review of Information Technology security program strategy, policy and processes. Self-motivated and a quick learner, constantly studying and training to keep abreast of new technologies on IT security.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Poonawalla Fincorp limited, Pune

**Employer:** PFL, from 16<sup>th</sup> Mar 2020 – Till date

Role: Working as Senior Manager Information Security, Security Architect

### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Develop, implement and monitor a strategic, comprehensive enterprise information security and IT risk management program to ensure that the integrity, confidentiality and availability of information is owned, controlled or processed by the organization.
- Provide strategic risk guidance for IT projects, including the evaluation and recommendation of technical controls.
- Manage security incidents and events to protect corporate IT assets, including intellectual property, regulated data and the company's reputation.
- Develop and oversee effective disaster recovery policies and standards to align with enterprise business continuity management program goals.
- Liaise among the information security team and corporate compliance, audit, legal and HR management teams as required.
- Assist resource owners and IT staff in understanding and responding to security audit failures reported by auditors.
- Consult with IT and security staff to ensure that security is factored into the evaluation, selection, installation and configuration of hardware, applications and software.
- Provide strategic risk guidance for IT projects, including the evaluation and recommendation of technical controls.
- Manage the day-to-day activities of threat and vulnerability management, identify risk tolerances, recommend treatment plans and communicate information about residual risk.
- Ensure audit trails, system logs and other monitoring data sources are reviewed periodically and comply with policies and audit requirements.
- Enforcing Corporate Policies and Governance.
- Risk Assessment and Mitigation for the identified risk across departments.
- Revision of Policies and SOP.
- Maintaining Regulatory Compliance.
- Maintaining ISO-27001:2005 Compliance.
- Internal and External Audit Information Security audit- Based on RBI master direction, ISMS audit based on ISO.
- Monthly Infosec PPT for CIO presentation.
- Implementing Security Awareness across organization.
- IT Projects related to Information Security.
- Monitoring and reviewing of SOC alerts SIEM.

Handling and Implementation of security tools like DLP,Zscaler-proxy, Crowdstrike-ATP,
 Vulnerability Assessment, Risk Assessment, Brand Monitoring etc.

# Hinduja Global Solution Limited, Pune

Employer: HGS, from 1st Sep 2015 – 31st Jan 2020

**Role**: Working as Service Delivery Manager-handling multiple accounts, leading team of 15+ engineer across sites

## **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Manage IT Infrastructure team to successfully build and sustain the IT infrastructure including network, servers, SAN, Backup System, VM, IP phone system, video conference and other IT infrastructure devices/systems.
- Responsible for implementing corporate IT policies, guidelines, procedures and standards to perform the overall infrastructure management, the relevant operations, the information security management and the service desk support.
- Manage IT infrastructure projects to ensure the project delivery being on schedule, on quality and within budget.
- Qualify IT infrastructure following risk assessment procedure, the protocols and change control process regulated by corporate IT.
- Managing Genesys Dialer and API Integration.
- Evaluated new and emerging security threats, products and technologies.
- Designed and maintained hosting and corporate network and telecommunications infrastructure.
- Installed, configured and maintained PCs, networking equipment and network operating systems.
- Enhancing professional relationship with customer to manage operational issues.
- Imparting regular technology updates to business/ site leaders.
- Responsible for Internal/External Audit related to account.
- Monthly CIO presentation and MIS reports.
- Hardware RAID Configuration.
- Worked on MacAfee Endpoint Encryption 5.5.
- Installation & Configuration Active Directory Domain Services (ADS/ADDS) and Group Policies.
- Antivirus management using McAfee (ENS, DE, DLP...).

- Working on incident request and change management with ITSM cloud-based ticketing tool
- Deploying virtual machine, assigning Disk, Ram, CPU, Network Adaptor, and VLAN.
- Attending daily status calls with different location managers.
- Handling & monitoring all the System and Network devices located at Data Centre through Solar Wind and Ops-Manager tool.

## **Projects Undertaken:**

- Setting Up New Contact Centre for various business-like Ecommerce, Telecom etc.
- Windows 7 To windows 10 Migration
- O-365 Migration
- SCCM Implementation
- Active member on the implementation of ISO-27001

## Mphasis an HP Company, Indore

Employer: Mphasis, from Dec 2008 - Aug 2015.

**ROLE:** - Lead Infrastructure Engineer

### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Site Spoc for the location handling multiple Telecom & Ecommerce Business
- Managing IT Operations, Change Management, Incident Management –Sev1, Sev2 etc.
- Analyze business requirements by Partnering with Key stake holders across the organization to develop solutions for IT needs.
- Integrate LAN, WAN, and server architecture.
- Site Implementation with Rack and stack and managing 1500 systems with 100% compliance.
- Maintaining proper Compliance like Antivirus and patch updation etc.
- Internal and External Audit clearance
- Vendor and Client co-ordination for any IT related responsibilities
- Guide systems administrators, network engineers and InfoSec personnel to solve and troubleshoot security and network issues more efficiently.
- Analyze the need of the business and plan solutions.
- Providing end user application software (MS Outlook, Antivirus (McAfee) etc.) and Operating System maintenance and upgrades, troubleshooting hardware and software support.

Inknowtech India Pvt. Ltd, Noida

Employer: Deployed at Mphasis Noida, from Aug 2007 - Dec 2008.

**ROLE:** -Senior Support Engineer

**RESPONSIBILITIES: -**

To maintain a LAN, WAN setup of around 1500 Desktops & Laptops with a team. Providing end user application software (MS Outlook, Antivirus (McAfee) etc.) and Operating System maintenance and upgrades, troubleshooting hardware and software support. Monitoring and updating all systems and servers with antivirus and Microsoft patches using tools like – McAfee and SCCM server. Handling a team of 8 Engineers.

Isource Infosystems Pvt. Ltd, Noida

Employer: Deployed at Mphasis Noida, from Sep 2005 - July 2007

**ROLE:** -Senior Support Engineer

**RESPONSIBILITIES: -**

To maintain a LAN, WAN setup of around 1500 Desktops & Laptops with a team. Providing end user application software (MS Outlook, Antivirus (McAfee) etc.) and Operating System maintenance and upgrades, troubleshooting hardware and software support.

**IGATE Global Solutions, Noida** 

**Employer**: From Apr 04 - Sep 2005

**Role:** – System Engineer

Responsibilities -

Desktop support engineer, installed, and administered Windows-based networks.

## **TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS**

MCSE-Training

ITIL- (Information Technology Infrastructure Library)

## **EDUCATIONL QUALIFICATIONS**

MCA Sikkim Manipal University in 2007.

BCA CCS University (UP) in 2002. .

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name : Mr. K.R. Mahto
Date of Birth : 17<sup>th</sup> Jan 1980
Mobile No : +91-9827892233
Languages Known : English and Hindi

Strengths : Positive & winning attitude & believe in teamwork.

Hobbies : Web Surfing on latest technologies, Listening music.

I here by declare that the above information's are true and to the best knowledge of mine.

### **Hiten Kumar**